

## Maryam Ashfaq

Software Developer

As an IT graduate with a passion for programming, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise and creativity to every project. With a keen eye for detail and a drive for innovation, I strive to develop cutting-edge solutions that push boundaries and exceed expectations.

maryamashfaq1828@gmail.com

Islamabad, Pakistan

in linkedin.com/in/maryamashfaq5

+92 324 5250505

maryam037.github.io/MaryamPortfolio/

github.com/maryam037

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Frontend Developer Intern

Teresol Pvt. Ltd.

07/2022 - 09/2022

Islamabad

## Intern

Inter Services Public Relations, GHQ

06/2024 - 07/2024

Rawalpindi

### **PROJECTS**

### Final Year Project

 LitterGo - Al Powered Flutter Mobile Application For Detection And Management Of Litter Dumps using Computer Vision.

#### To Do List

 Created a simple yet responsive To Do list website, where user can add, delete and clear completed task and if user wants to save them then login/register. Developed using Html, CSS and javascript.

## Android Videocalling App

 Created a video calling mobile app using agora.io's video SDK classes, implemented in Java. Offering reliable platform for high-quality video calls for real-time communication and seamless video streaming.

#### Skateboarding Website

 Using Tailwind CSS, React and Vite created a modern and responsive Skateboarding Blog website for beginners.

#### Shoes E-commerce Website

 Utilizing Tailwind CSS and MERN developed a visually appealing and responsive e-commerce website for an online shoe store.

#### Recipe Recommendation System

 Employed content-based filtering through feature extraction and cosine similarity to rank and suggest recipes based on user preferences, GUI developed using the tkinter library in Python.

# SKILLS



## **TOOLS**

Azure DevOps

**PowerBI** 

Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio

Browserstack

VS code

Android studio

Jupyter Notebook

## **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

**Bahria University** 

02/2020 - 06/2024

# Bachelor of Science in Computer Software Engineering(Exchange semester)

Altinbas University, Istanbul, Turkey

09/2021 - 02/2022

## **CERTIFICATES**

Data science in python - DataCamp (2021)

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Urdu

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Turkish

Elementary Proficiency